What if I told you there was a way
that you could make more sales,
you could do
less sales calls,
and overall become a lot more confident in
your ability to share
your pricing and get people to feel
compelled to join your paid program?
Well, it's pretty easy,
and even though it's easy, this
is still a fiercely debated
topic which so many people still can't
agree on.
At the end of the day, when someone
is considering doing business with you,
there
is an element of risk, and often
that risk is being held by the purchaser,
the
person on your sales page.
They're putting trust in you to deliver on
whatever it
is that they want. Now, there
is a way to offload
that risk to you to take it all
on your back,
but doing so does open you up a bit.
It can make you vulnerable,
and it could even cost you money and time.
So should you be offering a money-back
guarantee to those considering doing
business with you? First of all,
let's look at how a money-back guarantee
benefits
them,
the person considering doing business with
you.
Well,
it can reduce their insecurities to
finally getting over the line.
We have not only the difficult
consideration and racing questions in
their mind.
Is it good? Is it worth it?
Will they deliver?
We also then have the consideration
that the majority of people will
experience
buyer's regret, and this
is the moment that you purchase something,
you immediately
regret it and want money back in your bank
account.
This is simple loss aversion, which
is the psychological pain of losing
something.
It's twice as bad as the equivalent gain.
Humans hate losing things.
They also inflate the value of something
once it's theirs.
So if you're offered a money-back
guarantee, you could eliminate that entire
feeling.
This means in the onboarding process to
whatever it is you're doing, your
client isn't thinking about immediately
asking for their money back, which means
they can relax and settle into the course,
product, or service that you offer.
It's also worth noting
that for a lot of you in the current
territory you're
watching this from,
you may have to refund someone within 14
days due to their
consumer rights.
So you may as well offer the refund out
the goodness of your own
heart. Now,
if you have a really high refund rate,
this probably shows that your
product or service needs a rehaul.
If anything, these people
are then just doing free consumer research
for you.
To offer someone a money-back guarantee
puts the very person who's on your landing
page at ease. This also means that
if anyone feels like they want to book in
a
sales call or waste your time asking a
million questions, you can just say,
"Look,
there's a money-back guarantee. Sign up.
If you don't love it,
you can have your money back." This often
gets rid of the
time wasters, too.
If a money-back guarantee isn't enough for
them to do business
with you, trust me,
they're going to be a massive headache.
So how does a money-back guarantee benefit
you? Well, easy.
The majority of you feel like fucking
frauds.
You charge way more money than you would
ever pay someone to do the same thing.
Every time you get paid,
you look at your bank account like you
just pulled off a
fucking heist.
You experience guilt from payments more
than enjoyment, and you
quiver a bit when having to verbally
explain your pricing.
Offering someone a no-qualms money-back
guarantee means you can have the
confidence
in what it is that you're selling,
and that benefits you.
Imagine having a steak restaurant.
The person really wants the A5 Wagyu.
It's expensive, and he's umming
and ahhing about it.
And imagine being able to say to
that person, "Sir, this
is the best steak you'll
ever have,
or you can have your money back." The
truth is, unless the steak really
underperforms, which it shouldn't,
he's going to pay for it.
I do this with Neutonic all the time.
I know the product is so good
that the refund rate
is going to be way below the
cost per acquisition of each client.
To this day,
not one person has emailed me claiming
that they want their money
back.
We've had a few damaged via shipment
across Amazon, but that's a different
story altogether.
So how else does this benefit you?
Well,
they say if someone loves your product,
they'll tell one person, but if they
hate it, they'll tell 10. I'm not sure
if they actually say that.
I may have just made that up.
But in reality,
you don't want people out there with
a bad thing to say about your business.
I've actually had people I've refunded
give me business before.
Maybe a bit of guilt. Who knows?
You empower people to say,
"Do you know what?
It wasn't right for me,
but it could be great for you." There
is just no scenario
where running with someone else's money
and leaving them unhappy benefits you as a
brand. Ultimately,
offering a money-back guarantee means you
can generate more
sales. On the screen here
are two businesses that operate.
And in the last 12 months,
here's the revenue versus the refund rate.
A little bit of a flex, I know,
but it's important
that you see out of the amount
of cash that I'm making, how much of
that actually is in refunds.
As a percentage, it's small.
It's acceptable. It's expected.
If I asked you this,
would you accept a 4% refund rate
if it meant that you could
do two to three times the amount of sales
without having to do sales calls? Yes.
You need to have a bit of faith in
humanity.
Not everyone is a piece of shit looking to
exploit you.
The truth is, some people
are just happy to pay you money.
Some people like paying people to do a
good job.
Not only that,
sometimes we need to part with big chunks
of money to make us
accountable to actually doing the things
we've been told to do.
People don't respect free,
and they won't respect anything they pay
for and get
refunded.
And I'll leave you with the final example
of how this has worked for me
personally. Eight Sleep. I
was told about this cooling mattress,
people raving
about it in Austin,
Chris Williamson's friends. I saw it
was $2,500 US.
I thought,
"Fuck that." Went to the website just to
have a look at how expensive it
was. Then I saw something at the bottom,
30-day money-back guarantee.
My thoughts immediately changed from,
"Is this actually worth it?" to "This is
either the best sleep of my life,
or I get my $2,500 back." I was now
cornered into a position where I actually
had to buy.
And while looking back, I'm not sponsored,
but it was one of the best single
decisions of my life, maybe in that year.
Without that money-back guarantee,
I'd be sleeping with a sweaty gooch.
So why don't you take a bit of fucking
risk off your clients
and see how it impacts
your business? If it really doesn't help,
you can take it offline.
But so many of you
are letting your insecurities leave money
on the table and not
in your pocket. So
that should really help you with your
sales and conversions.
But what about growing your audience to
get even more people to get on your
landing
page to even see your offer? Well,
if you're someone that has under 10,000
followers or subscribers
and want to know all of the mistakes to
avoid, we should
click this video right here to help to
understand how you can do it right.
You note that I said avoid making
mistakes. Again, loss aversion.
Rather than telling you how to do it,
you tell not to do it.
Plays into human psychology. Anyway,
you click that, you enjoy it.